<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Created by Guided Data Capture (GDC) Software (http://www.trc.nist.gov)-->
<DataReport xmlns="http://www.iupac.org/namespaces/ThermoML" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.iupac.org/namespaces/ThermoML http://trc.nist.gov/ThermoML.xsd">
	<Version>
		<nVersionMajor>2</nVersionMajor>
		<nVersionMinor>0</nVersionMinor>
	</Version>
	<Citation>
		<eType>journal</eType>
		<eSourceType>Original</eSourceType>
		<sAuthor>Alopina, E. V.[Elena V.]</sAuthor>
		<sAuthor>Safonova, E. A.[Evgenia A.]</sAuthor>
		<sAuthor>Pukinsky, I. B.[Igor B.]</sAuthor>
		<sAuthor>Smirnova, N. A.[Natalia A.]</sAuthor>
		<sPubName>J. Chem. Eng. Data</sPubName>
		<yrPubYr>2017</yrPubYr>
		<dateCit>2017-04-20</dateCit>
		<sTitle>Correction to "Liquid Liquid Equilibria in Aqueous Mixtures of Alkylmethylimidazolium Glutamate with Potassium Carbonate and Some Physicochemical Properties of Aqueous [Cnmim][Glu] (n = 4, 6, 8) Solutions"</sTitle>
		<sAbstract>Aqueous biphasic systems containing ionic liquids (ILs) attract rather high attention; in particular their application in liquid liquid extraction is very attractive due to the specificity of the systems and great possibilities in the modification of IL chemical structures. In the present work, a series of amino acid ionic liquids (AAILs) based on the 1-alkyl-3-methylimidazolium cation and l-glutamic acid anion [Cnmim][Glu] (n = 4, 6, 8) were synthesized. Densities, refractive indices, and specific electrical conductivities of aqueous solutions of these AAILs in the concentration range 0 70 wt % (for [C4mim][Glu] solutions up to 87 wt %) were measured at temperature 298.15 K and ambient pressure 0.1 MPa. The liquid liquid equilibria for ternary solutions [Cnmim][Glu] + salt (K2CO3) + water at 298.15 K were under study. In aqueous solutions of [C8mim][Glu] micellization is observed, whereas [C4mim][Glu] and [C6mim][Glu] in aqueous solutions form small ordinary aggregates. The critical micellar concentration for [C8mim][Glu] aqueous solutions at 298.15 K was estimated from the experimental data on the concentration dependence of the specific electrical conductivities of the solutions.</sAbstract>
		<sDOI>10.1021/acs.jced.6b00906</sDOI>
		<sVol>62</sVol>
		<sPage>885</sPage>
	</Citation>
</DataReport>
